=Within The Grip=
=그립 내부=
=Episode 1=
=에피소드 1=
(My Husband is Missing)
(남편이 없어졌어요)
(Gu Mansion)
(구맨션)
(Brother Gu Zhaoxi's Spirit Tablet)
(구자오시 형제의 영혼 서판)
Zhaoxi.
자오시.
Stop.
멈추다.
(Crown Prince, Yin Zhou)
(왕세자, Yin Zhou)
You may go in peace.
안심하고 가셔도 됩니다.
The bamboo forest outside is bandit-infested.
밖에 보이는 대나무 숲 산적에 감염되었습니다.
The court has sent men to kill them.
법원은 그들을 죽이기 위해 사람들을 보냈습니다.
You are avenged.
당신은 복수했습니다.
(Eldest Young Master of the Gu family) I'll find your remains
(구 가문의 장남) 네 유해를 찾아줄게
(Gu Chaosheng) and make you have a proper burial.
(구조성) 그리고 당신의 장례를 제대로 치르게 해주세요.
(Yuluo, Xuanji Pavilion)
(Yuluo, Xuanji Pavilion)
(Virtue of Heaven and Earth)
(천지의 덕)
Master, all our men have returned.
주인님, 우리 부하들이 모두 돌아왔습니다.
(Xuan Qing, Xuan Unit of Xuanji Pavilion) No news of Master Zhaoxi.
(Xuan Qing, Xuanji Pavilion Xuan 단위) 자오시 선생님에 대한 소식이 없습니다.
Do you really want...?
정말 원하시나요...?
You and Master Zhaoxi aren't married yet.
당신과 자오시 선생님 아직 결혼하지 않았습니다.
There's no need to go this far.
여기까지 갈 필요는 없습니다.
Where's your young mistress?
네 젊은 여주인은 어디 있지?
Not here to offer incense for her husband?
향을 바치러 온 게 아니야 남편을 위해서?
Chaosheng, my husband isn't dead.
조성아, 내 남편은 죽지 않았다.
Why speak of offering incense?
왜 향을 바친다고 말합니까?
How dare you are in red to desecrate Zhaoxi's memorial?
어떻게 감히 빨간 옷을 입고 있니? Zhaoxi의 기념비를 모독하려고?
Guards! Seize her!
근위 연대! 그녀를 붙잡아라!
(Brother Gu Zhaoxi's Spirit Tablet)
(구자오시 형제의 영혼 서판)
Let all present bear witness.
참석한 모든 사람이 증언하도록 하십시오.
From this day forth, I, Gu Yuluo, take Gu Zhaoxi as my husband.
오늘부터 나 구위뤄는 구자오시를 남편으로 맞아주세요.
Death won't part us.
죽음은 우리를 갈라놓지 않을 것입니다.
I refuse to acknowledge his death until I find him.
나는 인정을 거부한다 내가 그를 찾을 때까지 그의 죽음.
No matter he is alive or dead, bring him to me.
그 사람이 살아있든 죽든 상관없이, 그를 나에게 데려오세요.
Impressive skills, Your Highness. But you left no survivors.
놀라운 기술이군요, 전하. 하지만 당신은 생존자를 한 명도 남기지 않았습니다.
This will hinder future investigations.
이는 향후 조사에 방해가 될 것입니다.
Survivors? I kept this one.
생존자? 나는 이것을 보관했다.
(Virtue of Heaven and Earth)
(천지의 덕)
Why involve yourself in this mess, Master?
왜 자신을 참여시키나요? 이런 혼란 속에서요, 마스터?
Is it for Master Zhaoxi? Or do you want to be Pavilion Master?
자오시 선생님을 위한 건가요? 아니면 파빌리온 마스터가 되고 싶나요?
Zhaoxi's fate remains unknown, but some have revealed their ambitions.
Zhaoxi의 운명은 아직 알려지지 않았습니다. 그러나 일부는 야망을 드러냈습니다.
Is this memorial truly for mourning?
이 기념물은 과연 애도를 위한 기념물인가?
Or just to declare him dead?
아니면 단지 그가 죽었다고 선언하기 위해서였나요?
Things have long changed in the Gu family.
상황이 오랫동안 변했습니다 구 가족에서.
But Master Zhaoxi...
하지만 자오시 선생님...
Without him, how will you control the Gu family?
그 사람 없이는 어떻게 지내요? 구 가문을 통제한다고요?
Keep searching.
계속 검색하세요.
If you can't find him, find someone who resembles him.
그 사람을 찾을 수 없다면, 그 사람과 닮은 사람을 찾아보세요.
Disguise is the specialty of our Xuanji Pavilion after all.
위장이 특기 결국 우리 Xuanji Pavilion의.
Why let that man escape, Master?
왜 저 사람을 도망치게 놔두세요, 마스터?
Aren't you afraid he'll report to his superiors?
두렵지 않나요? 그 사람이 상사에게 보고할 거야?
It doesn't matter. Do your duty.
그것은 중요하지 않습니다. 당신의 의무를 다하십시오.
Yes.
예.
(Gu Mansion)
(구맨션)
Thanks for leading.
이끌어주셔서 감사합니다.
(Tianlan, Crown Prince's secret guard) Just as you predicted.
(왕세자의 비밀 경호원 천란) 당신이 예측한 대로요.
(Gu Mansion)
(구맨션)
This man is useless now. Shall we keep him?
이 사람은 이제 쓸모가 없습니다. 그를 지켜줄까요?
Useless people
쓸모없는 사람들
get killed.
살해당하다.
(Three days later)
(3일 후)
(Zuixian Building)
(Zuixian 빌딩)
Gu Zhaoxi's wife...
구자오시의 아내...
Who else would do something like that?
또 누가 그런 일을 하겠습니까?
Trouble is brewing.
문제가 양조되고 있습니다.
Since the Crown Prince's death, the Emperor hasn't held court for days.
왕세자가 죽은 이후, 황제는 며칠 동안 법정을 열지 않았습니다.
Now, even Gu Zhaoxi...
이제 Gu Zhaoxi도...
That jinx.
그 징크스.
That jinx is here again.
그 징크스가 또 나왔네요.
Yeah.
응.
Master.
주인.
Chaosheng has been unusually quiet lately.
조성 최근에 유난히 조용했어요.
Any news of Master Zhaoxi?
Master Zhaoxi에 대한 소식은 없나요?
Those lookalikes you found are unsatisfactory.
그 닮은꼴들 당신이 찾은 결과는 만족스럽지 않습니다.
Any new ones?
새로운 것 없나요?
Not yet.
아직 아님.
Did you fail to find any,
아무것도 찾지 못하셨나요?
or did you not even try?
아니면 시도조차 하지 않았나요?
What brings you here so suddenly?
무슨 일로 갑자기 여기로 오셨나요?
Because someone taking my pay can't even find a lookalike.
누군가가 내 월급을 가져가니까 닮은꼴조차 찾을 수 없다.
You suspect the Gu family took part in the assassination.
구씨 일가를 의심하는군요 암살에 참여했습니다.
Could Gu Zhaoxi be the mastermind?
Gu Zhaoxi가 주인공이 될 수 있을까요?
Or was he killed afterwards?
아니면 나중에 살해된 걸까요?
And his wife, Mrs. Gu...
그리고 그의 아내 구여사...
The people all over the city praises her devotion.
도시 곳곳의 사람들 그녀의 헌신을 칭찬합니다.
But she is having fun here.
하지만 그녀는 여기서 즐거운 시간을 보내고 있습니다.
They say Gu Zhaoxi was constantly bedridden.
구자오시(Gu Zhaoxi)라고 하는데 끊임없이 침대에 누워 있었습니다.
Few ever saw him.
그를 본 사람은 거의 없습니다.
His wife doubted his death and searched for him secretly.
그의 아내는 그의 죽음을 의심했다. 그리고 그를 몰래 찾아다녔다.
That's how I obtained a portrait.
그렇게 초상화를 얻었습니다.
But she is seeking a replacement.
그러나 그녀는 대체자를 찾고 있습니다.
In that case,
이 경우
I'd like to meet
만나고 싶어요
this young madam.
이 젊은 부인.
Are you going to...
당신은...
Such a perfect opportunity
정말 완벽한 기회
must be used to thoroughly investigate
철저하게 조사하는 데 사용해야 합니다
the Gu family's intentions.
구 가문의 의도.
Master, I've discovered
선생님, 제가 발견했어요
Mrs. Gu comes from the Gus' Xuanji Pavilion.
구씨가 온다 Gus의 Xuanji Pavilion에서.
(Their mission is to gather intelligence and carry out missions.)
(그들의 임무는 정보를 수집하는 것입니다. 임무를 수행합니다.)
(The members are unfathomable.)
(멤버는 알 수 없다.)
(Can two people truly be so identical in this world?)
(정말 두 사람이 그럴 수 있을까? 이 세상에서는 너무 똑같은가요?)
(Or...)
(또는...)
The Gu family specializes in disguise.
구 가문은 변장을 전문으로 합니다.
They replaced your coachman and tried to assassinate you.
그들은 당신의 마부를 교체했습니다 그리고 당신을 암살하려 했죠.
They even created a face identical to yours at their place.
심지어 얼굴까지 만들어놨어 그 자리에서 당신과 동일합니다.
I wonder what they are plotting.
그들이 무슨 음모를 꾸미고 있는지 궁금합니다.
Investigate them,
조사해 보세요,
and then we'll know.
그러면 우리는 알게 될 것입니다.
Yes.
예.
What did you think of that dancer?
그 댄서에 대해 어떻게 생각했나요?
Beat him!
그를 이길!
Master.
주인.
Destiny governs all lives. We, too, are not masters of our own will.
운명은 모든 생명을 지배합니다. 우리도, 우리는 우리 자신의 의지의 주인이 아닙니다.
We can't follow our heart.
우리는 마음을 따라갈 수 없습니다.
What right do we have to meddle in the fates of others?
우리에게 무슨 권리가 있나요? 남의 운명에 개입하려고?
Zhaoxi.
자오시.
Don't be afraid. I'll bring you home.
두려워하지 마십시오. 집에 데려다줄게
Thank you. I came to the capital to visit my relatives.
감사합니다. 내가 왔어 친척들을 방문하기 위해 수도로 갑니다.
Bandits robbed me of all my traveling funds.
강도들이 나를 강탈했다 내 모든 여행 자금 중.
That's why...
그렇기 때문에...
If you have nowhere to go,
갈 곳이 없다면
why not return with me and secure employment?
나와 함께 돌아가는 게 어때? 그리고 안정적인 고용?
I'll provide for all your daily necessities,
내가 제공할게 모든 일용품을 구입하려면
settle your debts and arrange for your family's welfare.
빚을 청산하다 그리고 가족의 복지를 마련하십시오.
Upon completing my task, I'll reward you handsomely.
내 임무를 완수한 후, 후하게 보상해 드리겠습니다.
What task?
무슨 일?
Be my husband.
내 남편이 되어주세요.
(Fufeng Pavilion)
(푸펑 파빌리온)
How long has he bathed?
그 사람 목욕한 지 얼마나 됐어요?
As you ordered, it's been four hours.
주문한 대로 4시간이 지났습니다.
This man is suspicious. Please think carefully.
이 남자는 의심스럽습니다. 신중하게 생각해주세요.
Of course I know.
물론 알아요.
How could two people bear such resemblance in this world?
두 사람이 어떻게 견딜 수 있겠는가? 세상에 이렇게 닮았어?
And he happened to show up at this moment.
그리고 그는 일어났습니다 지금 이 순간 나타나려고.
But...
하지만...
We live by the blade.
우리는 칼날에 따라 살고 있습니다.
Why dread its edge?
왜 그 가장자리를 두려워합니까?
Xuan Qing must have already told you.
Xuan Qing이 이미 말했을 것입니다.
I need you to impersonate my husband, Gu Zhaoxi.
당신이 사칭을 해야 해요 내 남편 구자오시.
Once I find him
일단 그를 찾으면
or confirm his death, you may depart.
아니면 그의 죽음을 확인하고 떠나셔도 됩니다.
(I've heard the Gu family has four young masters.)
(구씨네 얘기는 들었는데 네 명의 젊은 마스터가 있습니다.)
(How can I get past them?)
(어떻게 지나칠 수 있나요?)
Even I'm not shy.
심지어 나는 부끄러워하지도 않는다.
Why are you shy?
왜 부끄러워해요?
We're going to play husband and wife.
우리는 남편과 아내 역할을 할 것입니다.
Besides,
게다가,
this is my room.
여기가 내 방이야.
Zhaoxi has been frail and bedridden since childhood.
Zhaoxi는 약했다 어린 시절부터 침대에 누워있었습니다.
His brothers trade far afield.
그의 형제들은 멀리 떨어진 곳에서 무역을 하고 있습니다.
He's not very close to his siblings.
그는 그의 형제자매들과 그다지 가깝지 않습니다.
So,
그래서,
he carries medicinal scents.
그는 약의 향기를 가지고 다닙니다.
Starting today,
오늘부터
you'll soak in herbal baths for four hours daily.
당신은 허브 목욕에 몸을 담그게 될 것입니다 매일 4시간 동안.
Since you resemble him quite a bit,
당신은 그 사람과 꽤 닮았으니까
I'll perfect your resemblance.
당신의 닮은꼴을 완벽하게 만들어 드리겠습니다.
Prolonged herbal baths may harm your health.
장시간 허브 목욕 건강에 해를 끼칠 수 있습니다.
You can get changed now.
이제 갈아입을 수 있습니다.
Lady, perhaps you should leave?
아가씨, 어쩌면 떠나야 할까요?
Still calling me "Lady"?
아직도 나를 "레이디"라고 부르나요?
Shouldn't you call me dear?
나한테 전화하면 안 돼?
♪Willows sway in the twilight breeze♪
♪버드나무가 황혼의 미풍에 흔들리네요♪
♪Ancient alleys guard time's secrets♪
♪고대 골목은 시간의 비밀을 지킨다♪
♪Bluestones bear life's imprints♪
♪블루스톤에는 생명의 흔적이 새겨져 있습니다♪
♪Falling petals, endless longing♪
♪떨어지는 꽃잎, 끝없는 그리움♪
♪Longing lingers within my heart♪
♪그리움은 내 마음속에 남아있습니다♪
♪Zither strings sigh for the sorrow parting♪
♪치터 현의 한숨 슬픈 이별을 위해♪
♪Past tales nest in my soul♪
♪과거 이야기가 내 영혼에 둥지를 틀고 있습니다♪
♪Affection lingers, unforgettable♪
♪애정은 잊혀지지 않습니다♪
♪Ink-stained scrolls recall bygones♪
♪잉크 묻은 두루마리는 과거를 회상합니다♪
♪Each stroke holds a thought♪
♪획 하나하나에 생각이 담겨있습니다♪
♪Prosperity fades like dreams♪
♪번영은 꿈처럼 사라져 버립니다♪
♪Past tales nest in my soul♪
♪과거 이야기가 내 영혼에 둥지를 틀고 있습니다♪
♪Affection lingers, unforgettable♪
♪애정은 잊혀지지 않습니다♪
♪Ink-stained scrolls recall bygones♪
♪잉크 묻은 두루마리는 과거를 회상합니다♪
♪Each stroke holds a thought♪
♪획 하나하나에 생각이 담겨있습니다♪
♪Prosperity fades like dreams♪
♪번영은 꿈처럼 사라져 버립니다♪
♪Past tales nest in my soul♪
♪과거 이야기가 내 영혼에 둥지를 틀고 있습니다♪